Pawan Roy

Gautam Buddha Nagar, Uttar Pradesh, India



pawanroy0066@gmail.com



8920443782



linkedin.com/in/pawan-roy-4a2964214

Summary

A Software Engineer specializing in Android SDK is a skilled professional who focuses on developing software applications for the Android operating system. This engineer possesses expertise in the Android Software Development Kit (SDK) and uses it to create, maintain, and optimize mobile applications for Android devices.

Key responsibilities include

- Designing and implementing user interfaces
- Integrating backend services
- Debugging and troubleshooting
- Ensuring compatibility across various Android versions and Screen sizes.

Experience

Software Engineer

One97 Communications Limited

May 2023 - Present (5 months)

Worked on the sub project of Paytm, India's most popular payment application Specifications

- 100M+ Downloads
- 100k+ daily active users
- 4.5 rating on playstore

Android Developer

Teckborn Technologies Pvt Ltd

May 2022 - May 2023 (1 year 1 month)

Worked on the project payRup the payment application.

Specifications

- 100k+ Downloads
- 10k+ Daily active users

Available on Playstore since 1 Jan 2023

Software Developer

MagicApps

Aug 2021 - Apr 2022 (9 months)

Android Developer Intern

Xatcovis Solutions Private Limited

Feb 2019 - Jul 2019 (6 months)

Android Developer Intern

ThePadosi

Sep 2018 - Nov 2018 (3 months) Worked on project Campustories Specifics of the App

- 30k Downloads
- 2k daily active users
- 4.1 rating
- Soical application based on CivicTech

Education



nr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam Technical University

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Electrical, Electronics and Communications Engineering Aug 2015 - Jul 2019

Licenses & Certifications



H Basic Java - HackerRank

Skills

Software Architecture • Flutter • Andorid • Volley • Jira • Confluence • Bitbucket • Slack • Jenkins • Software Design